Hello English learners.
英语学习者你们好。
Welcome back to EnglishPod.
欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today, we are going to be teaching you a very important technique, especially for
今天，我们要教你们一个非常重要的技巧，特别是
the guys if you want to have good luck with the ladies, right?
对男士们来说，如果你想在女士面前有好运气，对吧？
Oh, Marco.
哦，Marco。
Well, today's lesson is called that's flattering.
嗯，今天的课程叫做“真会说话”。
Right.
没错。
So we are going to be teaching you how to flatter someone.
所以我们要教你们如何恭维别人。
Okay.
好的。
So what does it mean to flatter someone?
那么，恭维别人是什么意思呢？
Well, basically, you're going to be giving compliments and you're going to make that
嗯，基本上，你会给出赞美，让那个人
person feel good about themselves.
自我感觉良好。
That's right.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
So flattering.
所以是恭维。
Now, before we get on with this flattering lesson, we need to look at some vocabulary
现在，在我们开始这堂恭维课之前，我们需要先看一些词汇，
in Vocabulary Preview.
在词汇预览部分。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
All right.
好的。
On Vocabulary Preview today, we have two small words.
今天的词汇预览里，有两个小词。
So the first one is bar exam.
第一个是“律师资格考试”。
The bar exam.
律师资格考试。
So the bar exam is that formal test that lawyers must do to become official lawyers.
律师资格考试是律师必须通过的正规考试，才能成为正式律师。
Right.
没错。
So it's that final exam in order to finally become a lawyer.
所以这是为了最终成为律师的结业考试。
Okay.
好的。
And what about our next word?
那下一个词呢？
Well, we're also going to hear in the dialogue obnoxious.
嗯，我们在对话中还会听到“令人讨厌的”。
Obnoxious.
令人讨厌的。
Okay.
好的。
So this is an adjective.
这是一个形容词。
Yes.
是的。
And it means something that is really, really annoying.
意思是某事物非常非常烦人。
Okay.
好的。
So something can be...
所以某事物可以……
So something can be obnoxious.
所以某事物可以是令人讨厌的。
Or someone.
或者某人。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So now we have these two words that we're going to listen to in the dialogue.
现在我们有了这两个词，我们会在对话中听到它们。
And now let's listen to two people as they flatter each other in our dialogue.
现在让我们听一下两个人在对话中互相恭维。
Valerie.
Valerie。
Hi.
嗨。
Wow.
哇。
How have you been?
你最近怎么样？
It's been such a long time.
好久不见了。
Oh, Marlene.
哦，Marlene。
Indeed, it's been a while.
确实，有一阵子了。
How have you been?
你最近怎么样？
Wow, you look amazing.
哇，你看起来棒极了。
I love what you've done with your hair.
我喜欢你做的发型。
Really?
真的吗？
Thanks.
谢谢。
I went to that hair salon you told me about, but enough about me.
我去了你告诉我的那家美发沙龙，不过别光说我。
Look at you.
看看你。
God, you haven't aged a day.
天哪，你一点都没老。
What is your secret?
你的秘诀是什么？
Come on.
说吧。
Well, I've been watching what I eat, and I work out three times a week.
嗯，我一直在注意饮食，而且每周锻炼三次。
By the way, I heard your son recently graduated.
顺便说一下，我听说你儿子最近毕业了。
Yes.
是的。
My little Paul is finally a doctor.
我的小Paul终于成医生了。
They grow up so fast, you know.
他们长得真快，你知道的。
He is such a handsome guy.
他真是个帅小伙。
He gets his looks from his mother, of course.
当然，他长得像他妈妈。
Thank you.
谢谢。
What about your daughter, Pamela?
那你女儿Pamela呢？
I heard she passed the bar exam and married recently.
我听说她通过了律师资格考试，最近还结婚了。
Oh, yes.
哦，是的。
She had a beautiful wedding in Cozumel, Mexico, and we all attended.
她在墨西哥科苏梅尔岛办了一场美丽的婚礼，我们都参加了。
Such a lovely girl.
真是个可爱的女孩。
I hope my Paul is lucky enough to find a girl like that someday.
我希望我的Paul有一天能幸运地找到像这样的女孩。
But of course.
当然会。
Well, it's been great talking to you, but I have to get going.
嗯，跟你聊天很开心，但我得走了。
Same here.
我也是。
We'll catch up soon, maybe over coffee.
我们很快再聚，也许喝杯咖啡。
That would be great.
那太好了。
Give me a call.
给我打电话。
See you soon.
再见。
Bye.
拜。
Ugh.
呃。
I cannot stand that woman or her obnoxious daughter.
我受不了那个女人和她那令人讨厌的女儿。
All right, so this is your typical, normal, everyday behavior that women show to each
好的，这就是女性之间典型的、正常的、日常的行为，
other, right?
对吧？
Yeah, I think it's very common.
是的，我觉得这很常见。
It's very hard to argue against this because I think everyone does it, or at least you've
很难反驳这一点，因为我觉得每个人都这样做，或者至少你
heard maybe your mother or your son talk to her friends like this, right?
可能听过你妈妈或你儿子这样和朋友说话，对吧？
So pretend you like a person who you actually hate.
所以假装你喜欢一个你其实讨厌的人。
Right.
没错。
You have to be courteous.
你必须彬彬有礼。
I don't know what you're doing to me now.
我不知道你现在对我做什么。
All right, no, I'm not.
好吧，不，我没有。
But we can take a look at some of this great language, very rich language that we found
但我们可以看看一些很棒的语言，非常丰富的语言，我们在
in this dialogue in Fluency Builder.
这个对话的流利度构建部分找到了。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
All right, we're doing things a little bit different in this lesson.
好的，这节课我们有点不同。
So we're going to do two Fluency Builders.
所以我们要做两个流利度构建。
And in the first one, we're going to focus on language you can use to flatter someone.
在第一个中，我们将专注于你可以用来恭维别人的语言。
Right.
没错。
So let's get started.
那我们开始吧。
In the very first part of the dialogue, we heard Valerie say, I love what you've done
在对话的最开始，我们听到Valerie说：“我喜欢你做的
with your hair.
发型。”
I love what you've done with your hair.
我喜欢你做的发型。
I love what you've done with.
我喜欢你做的……
Okay, so if somebody says this, basically they're saying, I like the change you made.
好的，所以如果有人这么说，基本上他们在说：我喜欢你做的改变。
Okay.
好的。
And change not only to your hair, right?
而且改变不只是发型，对吧？
It could be anything.
可以是任何东西。
So I love what you've done with your new house.
所以“我喜欢你对你新房子做的布置”。
Okay.
好的。
Or I can say, I love what you've done with your garden.
或者我可以说：“我喜欢你对你花园做的布置。”
It looks so beautiful.
它看起来太美了。
So something that you've changed, you can use this phrase for.
所以对于你改变的东西，你可以用这个短语。
Okay.
好的。
And in this case, it's her hair.
在这个例子里，是她的发型。
So she is complimenting her on her hair.
所以她在赞美她的发型。
We also heard Darlene say, you haven't aged a day.
我们还听到Darlene说：“你一点都没老。”
You haven't aged a day.
你一点都没老。
Okay.
好的。
So now she is saying that she hasn't gotten any older.
所以现在她在说她一点都没变老。
That's right.
没错。
To age is to get older.
“变老”就是年龄增长。
Okay.
好的。
So this is a very common way of telling somebody you look great.
所以这是一种很常见的告诉别人你看起来很棒的方式。
That's right.
没错。
You look young.
你看起来很年轻。
You look great.
你看起来很棒。
You haven't aged a day.
你一点都没老。
All right.
好的。
So then they talk about their kids and they're talking about the sun and they, and Valerie
然后他们聊到孩子，他们谈到儿子，Valerie
says he's such a handsome guy.
说：“他真是个帅小伙。”
He is such a handsome guy.
他真是个帅小伙。
Okay.
好的。
So this structure is important because now I can change the adjective and I am saying
这个结构很重要，因为现在我可以换形容词，说
he is very intelligent.
“他非常聪明。”
He is such an intelligent guy.
他真是个聪明的家伙。
That's right.
没错。
And then this is such a good day.
然后“今天真是个好日子。”
All right.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So now why don't we combine the two phrases that we've just heard?
那么，我们为什么不把刚听到的两个短语结合起来呢？
I love what you've done with and he is such a, and let's listen to some examples.
“我喜欢你做的……”和“他真是个……”，让我们听一些例子。
Example one.
例子一。
We love what you've done with this place.
我们喜欢你对这个地方的布置。
Such a beautiful room.
真漂亮的房间。
Example two.
例子二。
I love what you've done with your hair.
我喜欢你做的发型。
Such a nice color on you.
这颜色在你身上真好看。
Example three.
例子三。
I love what you've done with this space.
我喜欢你对这个空间的布置。
Such a wonderful garden.
真棒的花园。
Okay.
好的。
I really like how those two phrases can fit together.
我真的很喜欢这两个短语如何搭配在一起。
Yeah, they are very good and now you can use them together or separately like in the dialogue.
是的，它们非常好，现在你可以像在对话中那样一起或分开使用它们。
That's right.
没错。
Now let's move to our final flattering phrase.
现在让我们进入最后一个恭维短语。
Valerie says that Darlene's son gets his looks from his mother.
Valerie说Darlene的儿子长得像他妈妈。
Right.
没错。
She says he gets his looks from his mother, of course.
她说：“当然，他长得像他妈妈。”
He gets his looks from.
他长得像……
Okay.
好的。
So when she says he gets his looks from, she is saying his appearance.
所以当她说“他长得像……”时，她是在说他的外貌。
His positive appearance, his good appearance.
他积极的外貌，他好的外貌。
Right.
没错。
His good looks.
他的好相貌。
Okay.
好的。
So now we can change the noun and I can say he gets his intelligence from his father.
所以现在我们可以换名词，我可以说：“他的聪明才智遗传自他父亲。”
Right.
没错。
And then he gets his beautiful singing voice from his mother.
然后“他美妙的歌声遗传自他母亲。”
Okay.
好的。
So now typically you would say his mother, his father or maybe one of the grandparents,
所以通常你会说他的母亲、他的父亲，或者可能是祖父母之一，
right?
对吧？
Maybe, yeah.
也许吧，是的。
But you wouldn't say he gets his good looks from his brother.
但你不会说“他的好相貌遗传自他兄弟”。
No, no, no, no.
不，不，不，不。
No.
不。
Mother, father, grandma, grandpa.
母亲、父亲、奶奶、爷爷。
All right.
好的。
So now that we've covered four great ways of flattering someone, let's listen to this
现在我们已经涵盖了四种很好的恭维方式，让我们再听一遍这个
dialogue again but we're going to slow it down a little bit so you can pick up on these
对话，但我们会放慢一点速度，这样你就能抓住这些
phrases.
短语。
Valerie.
Valerie。
Hi.
嗨。
Wow how have you been?
哇，你最近怎么样？
It's been such a long time.
好久不见了。
Darlene.
Darlene。
Indeed.
确实。
It's been a while.
有一阵子了。
How have you been?
你最近怎么样？
Wow.
哇。
You look amazing.
你看起来棒极了。
I love what you've done with your hair.
我喜欢你做的发型。
Really?
真的吗？
Thanks.
谢谢。
I went to that hair salon you told me about but enough about me.
我去了你推荐的那家美发沙龙，不过别光说我，看看你。
Look at you.
看看你。
God, you haven't aged a day.
天哪，你一点都没老。
What is your secret?
你的秘诀是什么？
Come on.
说吧。
Well, I've been watching what I eat and I work out three times a week.
嗯，我一直注意饮食，每周锻炼三次。
By the way, I heard your son recently graduated.
顺便说一句，我听说你儿子最近毕业了。
Yes, my little Paul is finally a doctor.
是的，我的小保罗终于成了医生。
They grow up so fast, you know.
他们长得真快，你知道的。
He is such a handsome guy.
他是个很帅的小伙子。
He gets his looks from his mother, of course.
当然，他长得像他妈妈。
Thank you.
谢谢。
What about your daughter, Pamela?
你女儿帕梅拉呢？
I heard she passed the bar exam and married recently.
我听说她通过了律师考试，最近还结婚了。
Oh, yes.
哦，是的。
She had a beautiful wedding in Cozumel, Mexico and we all attended.
她在墨西哥科苏梅尔岛办了一场美丽的婚礼，我们都参加了。
Such a lovely girl.
真是个可爱的女孩。
I hope my Paul is lucky enough to find a girl like that someday.
我希望我的保罗有一天能幸运地找到像她这样的女孩。
But of course.
当然会。
Well, it's been great talking to you but I have to get going.
嗯，和你聊天很开心，但我得走了。
Same here.
我也是。
We'll catch up soon, maybe over coffee.
我们很快再聊，也许喝杯咖啡。
That would be great.
那太好了。
Give me a call.
给我打电话。
See you soon.
回头见。
Bye.
再见。
Ugh.
唉。
I cannot stand that woman or her obnoxious daughter.
我受不了那个女人和她那讨厌的女儿。
Okay, so we see a lot of great flattering language in this dialogue but we also have
好的，我们在对话中看到了很多很好的恭维语言，但也有一些
some really good language and phrases you can use in small talk in any situation.
非常好的语言和短语，你可以在任何场合的闲聊中使用。
Right.
对。
So maybe if you talk to a friend that you haven't seen in a while, we have some really
所以，如果你和一个很久没见的朋友聊天，我们有一些非常
great phrases for, as you say, small talk.
好的短语，正如你所说，用于闲聊。
So let's look at those now in Fluency Builder, part two.
那么现在让我们在流利度构建器第二部分中看看这些。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
Okay, so let's start with the first phrase.
好的，让我们从第一个短语开始。
She says, Valerie, hi, wow, how are you?
她说，瓦莱丽，嗨，哇，你好吗？
It's been such a long time.
好久不见了。
So basically here she's saying we haven't seen each other in a long time.
所以基本上她是在说我们很久没见了。
Right.
对。
But it kind of gives you that idea that she regrets not talking to her for such a long
但这有点让人感觉她后悔这么久没和她说话，
time.
时间。
Yeah, she wishes she could have talked to her.
是啊，她希望能和她聊聊。
It's been such a long time.
好久不见了。
How are you?
你好吗？
So a wonderful way to start a conversation.
所以这是一个开启对话的好方法。
So when they start talking about their kids, Valerie says, by the way, I heard your son
所以当他们开始聊孩子时，瓦莱丽说，顺便问一下，我听说你儿子
recently graduated.
最近毕业了。
Right.
对。
By the way, I heard your son recently graduated.
顺便问一下，我听说你儿子最近毕业了。
So this phrase, by the way, I heard, blah, blah, blah, is really, really useful.
所以这个短语，“顺便问一下，我听说，等等等等”，真的非常有用。
Right.
对。
Let's take a look at the first part, by the way.
我们来看看第一部分，“顺便问一下”。
So this is a way to connect two different ideas or to start a new topic.
这是一种连接两个不同想法或开启新话题的方式。
Exactly.
没错。
And now when she says, I heard your son recently graduated.
现在当她说，“我听说你儿子最近毕业了”。
So we use this phrase, I heard, when we've got information that we're not sure about.
所以我们用“我听说”这个短语，当我们得到不确定的信息时。
Right.
对。
And also you are demonstrating interest about a certain topic or a news event that you would
而且你也在表达对某个话题或新闻事件的兴趣，你想
like to know about.
了解更多。
Right.
对。
And so basically you're asking the other person, tell me about this.
所以基本上你是在问对方，跟我说说这个。
Right.
对。
So I can say, hey, by the way, I heard you got married.
所以我可以这样说，嘿，顺便问一下，我听说你结婚了。
So then I'd tell you all about my wedding.
那我就会告诉你我婚礼的所有细节。
Exactly.
没错。
OK, so this is a very common way of talking to someone or getting some more information
好的，所以这是一种很常见的与人交谈或从某人那里获取更多信息的方式。
from a person.
信息。
So let's listen to some more examples of by the way.
让我们听一些关于“顺便问一下”的更多例子。
Example one.
例子一。
By the way, I heard you've recently been promoted.
顺便问一下，我听说你最近升职了。
Example two.
例子二。
I heard your daughter just had a baby.
我听说你女儿刚生了孩子。
Congratulations.
恭喜。
Example three.
例子三。
Oh, I heard you just got back from holiday in France.
哦，我听说你刚从法国度假回来。
All right, now, since these two ladies don't like each other very much, they want to end
好了，现在，因为这两位女士不太喜欢对方，她们想结束
the conversation, right?
对话，对吧？
Right.
对。
They want to end the conversation.
她们想结束对话。
And, well, you want to end it in a polite way.
而且，嗯，你想以礼貌的方式结束它。
Right.
对。
So they use a really great phrase here.
所以她们在这里用了一个非常好的短语。
They said, it's been great talking to you, but I have to get going.
她们说，和你聊天很开心，但我得走了。
Right.
对。
So it's like, well, it's been great talking to you, but I have to get going.
所以就像，嗯，和你聊天很开心，但我得走了。
So it's been great talking to you.
所以和你聊天很开心。
I've enjoyed talking to you.
我很享受和你聊天。
Right.
对。
So this is a very polite, very subtle way of saying, hey, I have to go or bye, I can't
所以这是一种非常礼貌、非常委婉的方式说，嘿，我得走了，或者再见，我不能
talk anymore.
再聊了。
Yeah, when you say that, you know that the conversation is ending.
是啊，当你这么说的时候，你就知道对话要结束了。
Exactly.
没错。
Now, she says, I have to get going.
现在，她说，我得走了。
What does it mean?
这是什么意思？
Get going.
得走了。
That doesn't make much sense.
这听起来不太合理。
Basically, it just means leave.
基本上，它就是指离开。
Okay.
好的。
I have to leave.
我得走了。
I have to get going.
You should get going.
你该走了。
You're going to be late.
你要迟到了。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
Some really good small talk phrases that are useful in any situation.
一些在任何情况下都很有用的闲聊短语。
So why don't we hear them again?
那我们为什么不重新听一遍呢？
One more time by listening to the dialogue.
再听一次对话。
Valerie.
瓦莱丽。
Hi.
嗨。
Wow.
哇。
How have you been?
你最近怎么样？
It's been such a long time.
好久不见了。
Darlene.
达琳。
Indeed.
确实。
It's been a while.
好久不见了。
How have you been?
你最近怎么样？
Wow.
哇。
You look amazing.
你看起来棒极了。
I love what you've done with your hair.
我喜欢你新做的发型。
Really?
真的吗？
Thanks.
谢谢。
I went to that hair salon you told me about, but enough about me.
我去了你推荐的那家美发沙龙，不过别光说我。
Look at you.
看看你。
God, you haven't aged a day.
天哪，你一点都没老。
What is your secret?
你的秘诀是什么？
Come on.
别这样嘛。
Well, I've been watching what I eat, and I work out three times a week.
嗯，我一直在注意饮食，而且每周锻炼三次。
By the way, I heard your son recently graduated.
对了，我听说你儿子最近毕业了。
Yes.
是的。
My little Paul is finally a doctor.
我的小保罗终于当上医生了。
They grow up so fast, you know.
他们长得真快，你知道的。
He is such a handsome guy.
他是个很帅的小伙子。
He gets his looks from his mother, of course.
当然，他长得像他妈妈。
Thank you.
谢谢。
What about your daughter, Pamela?
那你女儿帕梅拉呢？
I heard she passed the bar exam and married recently.
我听说她通过了律师资格考试，最近还结婚了。
Oh, yes.
哦，是的。
She had a beautiful wedding in Cozumel, Mexico, and we all attended.
她在墨西哥科苏梅尔岛办了一场美丽的婚礼，我们都参加了。
Such a lovely girl.
真是个可爱的女孩。
I hope my Paul is lucky enough to find a girl like that someday.
希望我的保罗有一天也能幸运地找到这样的女孩。
But of course.
当然会的。
Well, it's been great talking to you, but I have to get going.
嗯，跟你聊得很开心，但我得走了。
Same here.
我也是。
We'll catch up soon, maybe over coffee.
我们很快再聚，也许喝杯咖啡。
That would be great.
那太好了。
Give me a call.
给我打电话。
See you soon.
回头见。
Bye.
再见。
Ugh.
呃。
I cannot stand that woman or her obnoxious daughter.
我受不了那个女人和她那讨厌的女儿。
All right.
好了。
Very good.
非常好。
So now you have a couple of phrases that you can use to flatter someone, be it your friend
所以现在你有一些可以用来恭维别人的短语，无论是你的朋友
or somebody that you know or anyone.
还是你认识的任何人。
And well, they are very, very useful and if you use them correctly, of course.
嗯，它们非常非常有用，当然，如果你正确使用它们的话。
Right.
没错。
And these phrases sound really honest and really natural, very native-like.
而且这些短语听起来非常真诚、自然，很有母语者的感觉。
Okay.
好的。
So, if you have any other questions or comments or if you want to share some other phrases
所以，如果你有任何其他问题或评论，或者想分享一些其他短语，
that you use to flatter people, come to our website at EnglishPod.com and leave them in
你用来恭维别人的短语，请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，并把它们留在
our comment section.
我们的评论区。
So Marco and I have to get going, but we're looking forward to seeing you on the website.
那么，马可和我得走了，但我们期待在网站上见到你。
Thanks for listening and until next time.
感谢收听，下次再见。
Bye.
拜拜。
Bye-bye.